Guide to the Theodore Thornton Munger Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Theodore Thornton Munger papers
1806-1947
MS 362
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9
(24 boxes, 1 folio)
Correspondence, writings, speeches, sermons, and other papers of Theodore Thornton Munger, author, preacher, and spokesman for liberal theology. Also included are papers relating to the Munger and Selden families. Of special interest are the papers throughout the collection which reflect on the many religious controversies in New England between 1870 and 1900 in which Munger became embroiled, particularly Congregational polity. Important correspondents include Elisha Mulford, Francis Bicknell Carpenter, Washington Gladden, Andrew Dickson White, and Horace Scudder.
Munger, Theodore Thornton, 1830-1910
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the estate of Rose Munger, 1947. Gift of the United Church on the Green, UCC, 2014.
Arrangement
Arranged in four series: I. Correspondence. II. Writings, Speeches, and Research Materials. III. Sermons. IV. Special Files.
Scope and Contents
The Theodore Thornton Munger Papers consists of the papers of various members of the Munger and Selden families, but primarily those of Theodore Thornton Munger. A Congregational minister, a writer, and an advocate of the "new theology," Munger was born in 1830 in Bainbridge, New York, the son of Dr. Ebenezer and Cynthia Selden Munger. He was educated at Cortland Academy in Homer, New York, where the family had moved in 1836, and entered Western Reserve College at Hudson, Ohio in 1846. The following year he enrolled in Yale College, class of 1851. Upon graduation he entered Yale Divinity School, studying briefly also at Andover Theological Seminary, and was ordained in 1856 at the Village Church, Dorchester, Massachusetts. As a result of his growing disenchantment with both the rigidities of the New England Theology and the current enthusiasm for revivals, Munger withdrew in 1860 from the Dorchester Church with the expectation that he would follow his friend Elisha Mulford into the Episcopal Church. Instead he preached on invitation at various churches in and around Boston while he read and reconsidered his theological beliefs. By 1864, however, he had decided to remain within the Congregational fold and accepted a call from Centre Church in Haverhill, Massachusetts. But his liberal theology again came into conflict with that of his congregation and in 1869 he resigned his pulpit in Haverhill and accepted a temporary appointment in Providence, Rhode Island (1869-1871), followed by three years at the Eliot Street Church in Lawrence, Massachusetts. As a result of the failing health of both Munger and his family, later discovered to have been caused by defective plumbing, he sought a more healthful climate in San Jose, California (1875-1877), where he organized a new congregation. He returned to New England in 1877 accepting the call from the Congregational Church of North Adams, Massachusetts, where Washington Gladden and Lewellyn Pratt had previously paved the way for a less traditional ministry. But because of the recent refusal of the Indian Orchard Council to install the Reverend James F. Merriam for what they considered wayward views on the question of the eternal punishment, there was an inordinate interest in the fate of Munger whose regard for the teachings of Horace Bushnell was widely known.
Thanks to the weighty words of Noah Porter of Yale, the council, presided over by Mark Hopkins, approved what the council at Indian Orchard had just rejected. Munger served North Adams until 1885, when he accepted a call from the United Church in New Haven, a position which he held until his retirement in 1901.
Munger was married in 1864 to Elizabeth Kinsman Duncan and, after her death, to Harriet King Osgood in 1889. Munger died in New Haven on January 10, 1910.
Though Munger was not an original thinker, he is remembered for his attempts to accomodate Christianity to Darwin's theory of evolution and for his open mindedness toward the critical methods of biblical scholarship which caused such a controversy at the end of the nineteenth century. Following Horace Bushnell and the English Broadchurchmen, Frederick Denison Maurice and especially John W. Robertson, Munger attempted to break through the sectarian adherence to the letter of dogma and creed, exemplified by the action of the Indian Orchard Council of 1877, and return to the more catholic spirit of early Congregationalism. This "new theology" made the covenant, not the creed, the individual conscience, not conformity to the letter of Scripture, the basis of Christian fellowship. These views gained a wide hearing in his book of sermons, The Freedom of Faith, published in 1883.
Munger's chief distinction was as a writer and preacher. Possessed an exceptionally graceful literary style, he was an eloquent spokesman for "liberal" Christianity. His rapport with the young and his ability to give fresh expression to traditioanl ideas is demonstrated by the remarkable success of On the Threshold (1880) and a companion volume, Lamps and Paths (1883). The former, in fact, was chosen as one of the twenty volumes selected from the best English and American authors for the Cambridge Classics. Other books by Munger include the Appeal to Life (1887), Character Through Inspiration (1897), Horace Bushnell, Preacher and Theologian (1899), and Essays for the Day (1904).
The Theodore Thornton Munger Papers provide important information on Congregational polity, the influence of the English Broad-church movement upon New England Calvinism and the concommitant move by some toward the Episcopal Church, and the issues raised by the "new theology." The collection is arranged into four series: CORRESPONDENCE; WRITINGS, SPEECHES & RESEARCH MATERIALS; SERMONS; and SPECIAL FILES. The first series, CORRESPONDENCE, contains letters to and from many persons prominent in nineteenth century religion and education including: Lyman Abbot, Felix Adler, Horace Bushnell, Timothy Dwight, Daniel Coit Gilman, Washington Gladden, Elisha Mulford (78 letters), Noah Porter, and Horace Scudder (35 letters). The correspondence with Scudder pertains to Munger's literary work and their mutual friend, Elisha Mulford. The letters of Mulford and Andrew Dickson White focus heavily upon church matters and theology. (For Munger's letters to Mulford, see the Mulford Family Papers, Historical Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library). In addition, there is some correspondence between White and Munger's biographer, Benjamin W. Bacon, about Munger, and some important correspondence between Bacon and Munger's daughter, Rosa Munger, also about Munger's life and work. Also of interest are the letters to Munger from his brother, John H. Munger about his service in the army during the Civil War, his business ventures, and politics in general.
WRITINGS, SPEECHES & RESEARCH MATERIALS contains both printed and manuscript copies of Munger's books, essays and speeches. Of special interest is the draft of a collection of sermons for an unpublished book, The Heart of Things and a scrapbook containing printed articles (many by Munger) on the "new theology." In addition, there are several "reminiscenses" by Munger of his early life and an interesting copy of a letter his father received at Yale (1814) from his own father.
SPECIAL FILES consists primarily of personal and family papers and memorabilia, including various honors and tributes by friends and parishioners as well as a folder of material pertaining to the Robert Hume Controversy.
For additional biographical materials see Theodore Thornton Munger: New England Minister by Benjamin Wisner Bacon.
Biographical / Historical
Theodore Thornton Munger: ordained in 1856, and served in Dorchester, Mass., until 1860; from 1864-1869 served in Haverhill, Mass., then resigned due to conflicts over his liberal theology; from 1869-1871 served in Providence, R. I., and from 1872-1875 in Lawrence, Mass.; moved to San Jose, Cal., in 1875; from 1877-1885 served in North Adams, Mass.; from 1885-1901 served in New Haven, Ct.; advocate of the "new theology" and author of numerous books.
Anglo-Catholicism; Congregationalism; Liberalism (Religion); New England theology; Theology; New England; New Haven (Conn.); United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Sermons; Clergy; Abbott, Lyman, 1835-1922; Adler, Felix, 1851-1933; Bacon, Benjamin Wisner, 1860-1932; Bushnell, Horace, 1802-1876; Carpenter, F. B. (Francis Bicknell), 1830-1900; Dwight, Timothy, 1828-1916; Fisher, George Park, 1827-1909; Gilder, Richard Watson, 1844-1909; Gilman, Daniel C. (Daniel Coit), 1831-1908; Gladden, Washington, 1836-1918; Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1856-1930; Hay, John, 1838-1905; Herrick, Samuel E. (Samuel Edward), 1841-1904; Hume, Robert Allen, 1847-1929; Mulford, Elisha, 1833-1885; Munger, John H.; Munger, Rosa M.; Munger, Theodore Thornton, 1830-1910; Noble, John W. (John Willcock), 1831-1912; Porter, Noah, 1811-1892; Scudder, Horace Elisha, 1838-1902; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918; Munger family; Selden family
- Correspondence, 1817-(1845-1908) 1929; Series I; 2' 4" (7 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  CORRESPONDENCE is divided into three subsections: "General Correspondence," "Family Correspondence," and "Correspondence of Others." "General Correspondence" consists of the correspondence of Theodore Thornton Munger and is arranged alphabetically by the name of the writer of the letter, followed by the letters written by Munger which are arranged alphabetically by the name of the person to whom the letter was addressed. Among the important correspondents not previously mentioned are: Benjamin W. Bacon, Francis B. Carpenter, George P. Fisher, Richard W. Gilder, Robert A. Hume, and John W. Noble.
  "Family Correspondence" consists of the correspondence among various members of the Munger, Duncan, and Selden families (except for Theodore T. Munger). The largest part of this section consists of the correspondence of Munger's daughter, Rosa, much of it pertaining to the work of her father. The section is arranged alphabetically by recipient.
  "Correspondence of Others" consists primarily of the correspondence of Benjamin W. Bacon, Munger's biographer. This section is also arranged alphabetically by the name of the recipient and includes letters from John Hay, Arthur T. Hadley, Andrew Dickson White, and S. E. Herrick.
  - Letters to T.T. Munger [and family]
    - A-C, 1860-1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abbott, Lyman, 1888, 1892, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Adler, Felix, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Allen, A.V.G., 1883-1900 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American Unitarian Association; Stone, George W., 1896 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Angell, James B., 1900 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Atlantic Monthly, editor, Bliss Perry, 1900-1907 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bacon, Benjamin W., 1913 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bacon, Frank, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Baker, Eleanor J.W., 1886 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Baker, Frank Woods, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Baldwin, Simeon E., 1881, 1885, 1886, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Barrows, John Henry, 1893, 1898, 1899, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Beach, D.N., 1899 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Blake, J. Vila, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Blodgett, J.D., 1896 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Brewer, Cyrus, 1856, 1857, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      General
      See also: Church Affairs: Village Church, Dorchester
    - Bushnell, Horace, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bushnell, Louisa, 1898, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Carpenter, DeWitt, 1895, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Carpenter, Francis B., 1855, 1857, 1860, 1861, 1863, 1874, 1884, 1889, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Century Magazine Editor: Gilder, R.W., 1877-1885 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      See: Gilder folder
    - Cheney, Mary Bushnell, 1895, 1899, 1901, 1904, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Church Affairs: Centre Congregational Church, Haverhill, Mass., 1869, 1863, 1866, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Church Affairs: Congregational Church, Newtonville, Mass., 1885 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Church Affairs: Congregational Church, No. Adams, Mass., 1871-1875 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Church Affairs: Eliot Church, Lawrence, Mass., 1861, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Church Affairs; High Street Congregational Church, Providence, Rhode Island, 1869, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Church Affairs: Miscellaneous, 1857, 1858, 1872, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Church Affairs: United Church, New Haven, 1885-1901 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Church Affairs: United Church, New Haven. Invitations to council, 1895-1900 (Box 1, Folder 30a)
    - Church Affairs: Village Church, Dorchester, 1855-1857 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      See also: Brewer folder
    - The Christian World (James Clarke), 1883-1889 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Clark, Francis E., 1881, 1899, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Clarke, William B., 1878, 1885, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - "The Congregationalist and Boston Recorder" [C.A. Richardson], 1872 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - D-K, 1851-1904 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Duncan, Caroline, [1866] (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Dwight, Timothy, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Eliot, Charles, 1892, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Eliot, Samuel A.; American Unitarian Association, 1903, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Fields, James T., 1873, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Fisher, George P., 1904 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Fletcher, W.I., 1874, 1877, 1883, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Fowler, Francis, 1857, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Fowler, John, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - French, Asa, 1881, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Gilder, Richard Watson, 1877, 1883, 1885, 1887, 1904, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Gladden, Washington, 1879-1880, 1883, 1885-1886, 1889, 1895, 1899, 1902, n.d (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Glover, Sarah M., 1857, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Gordon, George A., 1897, 1900, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Griffin, Edward H., 1885 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Hadley, Arthur T., 1900, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Hall, Charles Cuthbert (Union Theological Seminary), 1899, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Hamlin, Cyrus, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Hardy, Alpheus, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Harper, William R., 1902 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Harris, George, 1889, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Harris, Robert, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Hazard, M.C., editor, Editorial Department, Congregational Sunday School & Publications Society, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Herrick, Edward C., 1858 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Hewitt, W.T., 1899 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Hillyer, M. Bushnell, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Hodges, George, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Hopkins, Washlawn E., 1904 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Hoppin, James Mason, 1899, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Hume, Robert A., 1886, 1887, 1908, 1909, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Huntington, W.R., 1899, 1903, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Ives, W.A., 1885 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Jenkins, T.L., 1877 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Jessup, Henry Harris, 1852, 1853, 1864, 1866, 1870, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Kingsley, J.D., 1872, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - L-N, 1863-1908 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Lawrence, William, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Mabie, F.W., 1887, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Means, Stewart, 1889-1900 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Merriman, Donald, 1883, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Merriam, James F., 1878, 1895, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Miles, Harry, 1899-1900 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Mitchell, Donald G., 1891 1899, 1903, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Morris, George P., 1902, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Morrison, J.H., 1857, 1872 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Mulford, Elisha, 1855, 1856, 1859-1861, 1864-1884, undated (Box 2, Folder 83-87)
    - Munger, Antoniette, 1855, 1860, 1867, 1892, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Munger, Chattie, 1867 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Munger, Cynthia Selden (mother), 1855, 1858, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Munger, David Selden, 1854, 1858, 1859, 1867, 1872, 1877, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Munger, Ebenezer, 1854-1857 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Munger, Elizabeth D., 1865-1872 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Munger, John H., 1851-1860, 1863, 1864, 1870 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Munger, John H., 1871-1876, 1878, 1879, 1888, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Munger, Philomeona, 1852-1855, 1858, 1859, 1867, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Rebecca (Aunt), [1869] (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Munger, Rosa, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Newton, William Wilbaforce, undated (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Nichols, James Robinson, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Noble, John W., 1852, 1853, 1893, 1900, 1902, 1903, 1908, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Oster, William, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - P-Z, 1852-1908 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Park, Edward A., 1856 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Parker, Edward P., 1885, 1900, 1904, 1905, 1907, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Parsons, Lewis Baldwin, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 105a)
    - Peabody, Francis G., 1903, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Phelps, Edward John, undated (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Phelps, William Lyon, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Porter, Noah, 1876, 1877, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Potter, H.C., 1893, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Potwin, T.S., 1877, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Rice, Richard A., 1891, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Robinson, J.D., 1886, 1887, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Schussman, J.G., 1901 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Scudder, Horace E., 1870-1872, 1880, 1883, 1885-1889, 1892, 1895, 1896, 1899 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Selden, Bertha, 1865, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Selden, D., 1860 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Selden, Edward D., 1869, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Selden, Gertrude E., 1848-1856, 1858, 1860, 1865, 1867, 1874 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Selden, Silas R., 1855 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Selden, William, 1856 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Smith, Cynthia M., 1854 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Smith, Cynthia Munger, 1855-1857, 1860, 1872, 1887 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Smith, Henry Preserved, 1899, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Smyth, Newman, 1885, 1886, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Sprague, Homer Baxter, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Stedman, Edward C., 1892, 1895, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Storrs, R.S., 1856-1857, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Sturtevant, J.M., 1870, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Taft, Theodore M., 1899 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Thayer, Henry B., 1877, 1883, 1885-1887, 1895 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Thorn, Samuel G. and Mrs. T., 1886 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Titus, L.A. (Mrs.), [1862] (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Todd, John Edwards, 1868, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Twichell, Joseph H., 1896, 1899, 1904, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Twining, Kinsley, 1883, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Twombly, Alexander S., 1877, 1883, 1886 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - V-W, 1879-1908 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Warner, Charles Dudley (Library of the World's Best Literature), 1883, 1885, 1888, 1892, 1896, 1899 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Washington, Booker T., 1905 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Wheeler, A.W., 1872 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Wheeler, Benjamin J., 1892 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - White, Andrew Dickson, 1850-1900 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - 1901-1908 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Whiton, James M., 1877, 1883, 1885, 1887 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Withington, Leonard, 1866, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Williams, Mary H., 1886, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Unidentified, 1862-1893 (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - Letters from T.T. Munger
    - Abbott, Lyman (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Baker, Eleanor J.W., 1857, 1858 (Box 4, Folder 151)
      - 1860-1890 (Box 4, Folder 152-158)
    - Crane, Thomas Frederick, 1899 (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Custer, Elizabeth B., 1891 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - Duncan, Marie, 1872 (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - to the Editor of Century Magazine, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - Haines, Miss, 1860-1863, 1866 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - Harris, Robert, 1871-1876 (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - Herrick, Edward C., [1858] (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Houghton, Mifflin Co., 1998 (Box 4, Folder 165a)
    - Jenkins, J. L., 1855-1857 (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - Merriam, James F., 1903 (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Morris, George P., 1906 (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Munger, Cynthia, 1865-1867 (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Munger, Cynthia, Eben, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Munger, Elizabeth D., 1866, 1868-1885 (Box 4, Folder 171-178)
    - Munger, Rosa, 1874, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - Noble, John W., 1851, 1852, 1896, 1902, 1903 (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - to others, 1860-1908 (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - Scudder, Horace E., 1871, 1872, 1874, 1878, 1880, 1882-1889, 1895, 1897, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Society of Christian Endeavor, 1886, 1887 (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1904 (Box 5, Folder 183a)
      See also: Mulford folder
  - Family Correspondence
    - Baker, Eleanor J. W. -- from Munger, Elizabeth Duncan, 1864, 1875, 1876 (Box 6, Folder 184)
    - Baker, Eleanor J.W. -- from Munger, John H., 1863 (Box 6, Folder 185)
    - Borden, Jenny -- from Munger, Elizabeth Duncan, 1863-1867 (Box 6, Folder 186)
    - 1868-1885 (Box 6, Folder 187)
    - Duncan, Carrinna -- from Munger, Elizabeth Duncan, 1866, 1881, 1884 (Box 6, Folder 188)
    - Duncan, James H. -- from Duncan, Rosanna, [1859] (Box 6, Folder 189)
    - Duncan, Marie (Mrs. James) -- from Munger, Elizabeth Duncan, 1870, 1884, 1885 (Box 6, Folder 190)
    - Duncan, Rosanna -- from Duncan, James H., 1860 (Box 6, Folder 191)
    - Duncan, Rosa and Elizabeth -- from Duncan, James H., 1850 (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Harris, Mary Duncan -- from Munger, Elizabeth Duncan, 1864-1868, 1870-1874, 1877 (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - Munger Family -- from Munger, Emma, [1905] (Box 6, Folder 194)
    - Munger Family -- from Munger, Thornton T., 1897 (Box 6, Folder 195)
    - Munger, Antoniette -- from Munger, Elizabeth Duncan, 1866 (Box 6, Folder 196)
    - Munger, Cynthia Selden -- from Munger, Ebenezer, 1856 (Box 6, Folder 197)
    - Munger, Cynthia Selden -- from Munger, Elizabeth Duncan, 1864-1868 (Box 6, Folder 198)
    - Munger, Elizabeth Duncan -- from Duncan, Caroline [cousin], 1864, 1873, 1875, 1882 (Box 6, Folder 199)
    - Munger, Elizabeth Duncan -- from Duncan, James H., 1859, 1860, 1863, 1864, 1866, 1867 (Box 6, Folder 200)
    - Munger, Elizabeth Duncan -- from Duncan, Marie (Mrs. James), 1855, 1858, 1859, 1861, 1864, 1870, 1871, 1873, 1874-1876, 1879-1885 (Box 6, Folder 201)
    - Munger, Elizabeth Duncan -- from Duncan, Rosanna, [1857-1860] (Box 6, Folder 202)
    - Munger, Elizabeth Duncan -- from Harris, Mary Duncan, 1858 [1865] (Box 6, Folder 203)
    - Munger, Elizabeth Duncan -- from Harris, Robert, 1864, 1865 (Box 6, Folder 204)
    - Munger, Harriet -- from Baldwin, Simeon E., 1910, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 205)
    - Munger, Harriet -- from Hume, Robert E., 1914 (Box 7, Folder 206)
    - Munger, Harriet -- from White, Andrew D., 1913 (Box 7, Folder 207)
    - -- Munger, Harriet, 1892, 1895, 1897, 1899, 1901, 1903, 1911, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 208)
    - Munger, Harriet -- sympathy B-W, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 209)
    - Munger, Polly, 1886 (Box 7, Folder 210)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Bacon, Benjamin W. (Biographical Material), 1913-1914 (Box 7, Folder 211)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Baker, Eleanor J.W., 1880, 1897, 1898, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 212)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Bradford, Gamaliel; Chace, Ada H., 1906, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 213)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Denny, Emily G., 1891, 1895, 1896, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 214)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Duncan, Caroline, undated (Box 7, Folder 215)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Fairbanks, Bessie M.; Goodrich, Jennie Paul, 1898, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 216)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Gordon, George A., 1896, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 217)